Summary

Passionate front-end web developer with more than 4 years of experience in building and maintaining responsive websites, including user requirements gathering, producing code and enhancing designs. Achieves compatibility targets while meeting and exceeding customer demands.

Experience

Senior Business Technology Associate Consultant (2018-03 – Current) ZS Associates India Private Limited, Gurgaon, HR

- Lead the team of 10 engineers and completely build the Frontend designs with API services integration for the company's major client portfolios.
- Developed different Web Portals like Sales Planning, Meeting Analytics, Call Planning, Internal Assets like REVO, Javelin and Competency Leadership Assessment.
- Involved in all major product-level design discussions. Also, collaborated with project stakeholders during development processes to confirm creative proposals and design best practices for the solution.
- Worked on 30+ projects in different domain areas and clients having 85% customer Satisfaction ratio after delivery.
- Delivered engaging and visually compelling web designs with user-friendly UI that are cross-browser compatible and mobile responsive.
- Generated and managed cohesive design quality across different projects, adhering to prescribed themes and functional choices.
- Experience in all phases of Software Development Life Cycle including Analysis, Design, Development, Documentation, Testing, Deployment, Version Control and Product Support.
- Good knowledge of Agile best practices, including project workflow, site deployment and release practices/scheduling.
- Knowledge of Git practices via Bitbucket, Azure, git bash (command-line), git desktop (and other git clients).
- Also responsible for code review, training and supervision of team members on projects.
- Used programming capabilities in Angular 7+, Bootstrap, Antdesign Systems, Graph Libraries, SQL and JavaScript and other libraries as needed.

Software Developer (2017-06 – 2018-02)

Astrea IT Services, Noida, UP

- Requirement gathering from clients.
- Demonstrating useful data in easy to read and understandable format.
- Improved data gathering, analysis and visualization procedures with strategic optimizations.

ARPIT AGARWAL

Lead Frontend Developer

Contact

Address

C 23/102 Surya Enclave Dayalbagh, Agra, 282005

Phone

9582213228

Email

arpit.04061995@gmail.com

LinkedIn

www.linkedin.com/in/arpitagarwal-040695

Skills

- HTML5
- CSS/LESS/SCSS
- Flexbox
- Bootstrap
- Ant-design Systems
- Angular 7+
- Javascript
- Agile Workflow Processes
- Version Control
- SQL
- Klipfolio
- MS Office
- Pvthon*
- Jasmine and Karma*

- Developed intelligence-sharing dashboards, providing company-wide access to collected data.
- Generated reports, updated spreadsheets and presented results.
- Collected data from wide-ranging sources, including Spreadsheet, Google Analytics, Facebook, Shopify, etc. using Klipfolio Software or Python Programs.
- Retrieved and manipulated data across different timeframes.

Education

2013-08 -	B.Tech: Information Technology
2017-06	Dr. A.P.J. Abdul Kalam Technical University

Graduated with 80.2%

2012-04 - **Intermediate** 2013-06 C.B.S.E.

• Scored 82.2%

2010-04 - **High School** 2011-06 C.B.S.E.

• Scored 9.2 CGPA

Side Projects

- Common Components: Developed a private common library for my current organisation using Ant-design System and Javascript from which we can directly import components as per the client need.
- **Book a Wine:** Book the professional bar services at your doorsteps.

Accomplishments

- Got Impact Recognition 2 times while working in ZS.
- Won 2nd prize in AD MAD in EPOQUE'15.
- Won 2nd prize in MUSICAL THEATRE in CULTURAL FEST'16.
- Won 3rd prize in FACE PAINTING in EPOQUE'16.
- Won 3rd prize in PHOTOGRAPHY in EPOQUE'16.
- An active participant as well as coordinator in different competitions organized at the college level.
- Instructor at Python Hobby Club in Department.

Certifications

- Online Certification in Bootstrap by Coursera
- Online Certification in Angular by Coursera
- Klipfolio Certified Expert
- Database training by EDx (Microsoft)
- Online training in Python by EDx (MITx)